<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Short_papers on Archit Patke</title><link>https://apatke.github.io/short_papers/</link><description>Recent content in Short_papers on Archit Patke</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apatke.github.io/short_papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>QLM: Queue Management for Large Language Model Serving</title><link>https://apatke.github.io/short_papers/aiops2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://apatke.github.io/short_papers/aiops2024/</guid><description>The emergence of large language models (LLMs) has introduced new computational demands for cloud service providers. LLMs have an auto-regressive nature that impacts decision-making for traditional resource provisioning mechanisms (RPMs). We introduce QLM: a queue management system that enables decision-making for RPMs targetting LLM serving. QLM consists of the LLM request waiting queue, optimizer loop, and RPMs enabled by the downstream LLM serving system. Incoming requests join the request queue, are assigned priorities by the optimizer, and then sent to the LLM serving system that actuates the RPMs.</description></item><item><title>Evaluating hardware memory disaggregation under delay and contention</title><link>https://apatke.github.io/short_papers/ipdps2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://apatke.github.io/short_papers/ipdps2022/</guid><description>Hardware memory disaggregation is an emerging trend in datacenters that provides access to remote memory as part of a shared pool or unused memory on machines across the network. Memory disaggregation aims to improve memory utilization and scale memory-intensive applications. Current state-of-the-art prototypes have shown that hardware disaggregated memory is a reality at the rack-scale. However, the memory utilization benefits of memory disaggregation can only be fully realized at larger scales enabled by a datacenter-wide network.</description></item></channel></rss>