<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publications on Archit Patke</title><link>https://apatke.github.io/publications/</link><description>Recent content in Publications on Archit Patke</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apatke.github.io/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Queue Management for SLO-oriented Large Language Model Serving</title><link>https://apatke.github.io/publications/socc24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://apatke.github.io/publications/socc24/</guid><description>Large language model (LLM) serving is becoming an increasingly critical workload for cloud providers. Existing LLM serving systems focus on interactive requests, such as chatbots and coding assistants, with tight latency SLO requirements. However, when such systems execute batch requests that have relaxed SLOs along with interactive requests, it leads to poor multiplexing and inefficient resource utilization. To address these challenges, we propose QLM, a queue management system for LLM serving.</description></item><item><title>Delay Sensitivity-driven Congestion Mitigation for HPC Systems</title><link>https://apatke.github.io/publications/ics2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://apatke.github.io/publications/ics2021/</guid><description>Modern high-performance computing (HPC) systems concurrently execute multiple distributed applications that contend for the high-speed network leading to congestion. Consequently, application runtime variability and suboptimal system utilization are observedin production systems. To address these problems, we propose Netscope, a congestion mitigation framework based on a novel delay sensitivity metric that quantifies the impact of congestionon application runtime. Netscope uses delay sensitivity estimates to drive a congestion mitigation mechanism to selectively throttle applications that are less susceptible to congestion.</description></item><item><title>Measuring Congestion in High-Performance Datacenter Interconnects</title><link>https://apatke.github.io/publications/nsdi2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://apatke.github.io/publications/nsdi2020/</guid><description>While it is widely acknowledged that network congestion in High Performance Computing (HPC) systems can significantly degrade application performance, there has been little to no quantification of congestion on credit-based interconnect networks. We present a methodology for detecting, extracting, and characterizing regions of congestion in networks. We have implemented the methodology in a deployable tool, Monet, which can provide such analysis and feedback at runtime. Using Monet, we characterize and diagnose congestion in the world’s largest 3D torus network of Blue Waters, a 13.</description></item></channel></rss>