<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publications on Archit Patke</title><link>https://apatke.github.io/publications/</link><description>Recent content in Publications on Archit Patke</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://apatke.github.io/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Measuring Congestion in High-Performance Datacenter Interconnects</title><link>https://apatke.github.io/publications/nsdi2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://apatke.github.io/publications/nsdi2020/</guid><description>While it is widely acknowledged that network congestion in High Performance Computing (HPC) systems can significantly degrade application performance, there has been little to no quantification of congestion on credit-based interconnect networks. We present a methodology for detecting, extracting, and characterizing regions of congestion in networks. We have implemented the methodology in a deployable tool, Monet, which can provide such analysis and feedback at runtime. Using Monet, we characterize and diagnose congestion in the world’s largest 3D torus network of Blue Waters, a 13.</description></item><item><title>A Study of Network Congestion in Two Supercomputing High-Speed Interconnects</title><link>https://apatke.github.io/publications/hoti2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://apatke.github.io/publications/hoti2019/</guid><description>Network congestion in high-speed interconnects is a major source of application runtime performance variation. Recent years have witnessed a surge of interest from both academia and industry in the development of novel approaches for congestion control at the network level and in application placement, mapping, and scheduling at the system-level. However, these studies are based on proxy applications and benchmarks that are not representative of field-congestion characteristics of high-speed interconnects. To address this gap, we present (a) an end-to-end framework for monitoring and analysis to support long-term field-congestion characterization studies, and (b) an empirical study of network congestion in petascale systems across two different interconnect technologies: (i) Cray Gemini, which uses a 3-D torus topology, and (ii) Cray Aries, which uses the DragonFly topology.</description></item></channel></rss>